extraspace.com 2019-03-22

# Privacy Statement and Legal Disclaimer for Extra Space Storage

**Last Updated: August 21, 2018**

This privacy policy (this “ ** _Policy_** “) describes the collection of personal information by Extra Space Storage Inc., a Maryland corporation (“ ** _Company_** ,” “ ** _we_** ,” or “ ** _us_** “) from users of our website at www.extraspace.com (the “ ** _Website_** “), as well as all related applications, widgets, software, tools, and other services provided by us and on which a link to this Policy is displayed (collectively, together with the Website, our “ ** _Services_** “). This Policy also describes our use and disclosure of such information. This Policy is incorporated by reference into the Company Terms of Use (available at https://www.extraspace.com/policies/terms.aspx) and subject to the provisions of the Terms of Use.

**Personal Information**

“ ** _Personal Information_** ,” as used in this Policy, is information that specifically identifies an individual, such as an individual’s name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address. Personal Information also includes information about an individual’s activities, such as information about his or her activity on our Services, and demographic information, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area, and preferences, when any of this information is linked to Personal Information that identifies that individual.

Personal Information does not include “aggregate” or other non-personally identifiable information. Aggregate information is information that we collect about a group or category of products, services, or users that is not personally identifiable or from which individual identities are removed. We may use and disclose aggregate information, and other non-personally identifiable information, for various purposes.  
**  
Privacy Principles**

We follow the following principles in order to protect your privacy:

  * We do not collect any more Personal Information about you than is necessary;
  * We only use your Personal Information for the purposes we specify in this Policy, unless you agree otherwise;
  * We do not keep your Personal Information if it is no longer needed; and
  * Other than as we specify in this Policy, we do not share your Personal Information with third parties.

**Collection of Information**  
__  
__ We collect Personal Information from you in the following ways. We do so to fulfill our contractual obligations (such as providing the Services) and for our legitimate business purposes (such as improving the Website and Services). We may also collect Personal Information with your consent.

_Voluntarily-Provided Information_

We collect Personal Information that our users provide to us in a variety of ways on our Services. These include the following:

  * _E-mail Newsletters_. We may offer e-mail newsletters from time to time on our Services. If you sign up to receive a newsletter from us, we collect your e-mail address.
  * _User Accounts and Profiles_. Our Services may give you the ability to register for a Company account or to create and update a user profile on the applicable Service. If we offer user-account or profile functionality on the Services, we will collect the Personal Information that you provide to us in the course of registering for an account or creating or updating a user profile. This information may include, for example, name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address, and related demographic information about you. We may indicate that some personal information is required for you to register for the account or to create the profile, while some is optional.
  * _Interactive Features_. Our Services may contain interactive functionality that allows you to engage with other users on the Services, post comments to forums, to upload user information and other content (the “ ** _User Materials_** “) to your account, participate in surveys, and otherwise to interact with the Services and with other users. If you use any interactive functionality on our Services that request or permit you to provide us with personal information (including, for example, any services that allow you to post User Materials on any of our Services), we collect the Personal Information that you provide to us in the course of using these interactive features.
  * _Correspondence_. If you contact us by e-mail, using a contact form on the Services, or by mail, fax, or other means, we collect the Personal Information contained within, and associated with, your correspondence.
  * _Contests and Sweepstakes_. We or our advertisers and other business partners may conduct or sponsor special contests, sweepstakes, and other promotions that users may enter or otherwise participate in on our Services. Certain of these promotions may be co-branded with one of our advertisers or other business partners. In these instances, the collection of your Personal Information may occur directly by the third-party partner on its website or other online service and may be shared with us. The promotion will state the privacy policy or policies governing the collection of such personal information.

_Passively-Collected Information_

When you visit our Services, some information is collected automatically. For example, when you access our Services, we automatically collect your browser’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type, the nature of the device from which you are visiting the Services (e.g., a personal computer or a mobile device), the identifier for any handheld or mobile device that you may be using, the website that you visited immediately prior to accessing any Web-based Services, the actions you take on our Services, and the content, features, and activities that you access and participate in on our Services. We also may collect information regarding your interaction with e-mail messages, such as whether you opened, clicked on, or forwarded a message.

We may collect this information passively using technologies such as standard server logs, cookies, and clear GIFs (also known as “Web beacons”). We use passively-collected information to administer, operate, and improve the Website and our other services and systems, to improve the effectiveness of advertising on our Services, and to provide advertisements and other content that is tailored to you. We may also use cookies on the Website in order to deliver our online advertising through third-party vendors, including Google, on a variety of sites on the internet. If we link or associate any information gathered through passive means with Personal Information, or if applicable laws require us to treat any information gathered through passive means as Personal Information, we treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Policy. Otherwise, we use and disclose information collected by passive means in aggregate form or otherwise in a non-personally identifiable form.

You may opt out of receiving cookie-based advertising from Google by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/) and/or from other third party vendors by visiting the [Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). You may also modify your cookie settings in your browser through your browser settings. Please note that if you set your browser to disable cookies you may not be able to fully access and use the Services.

Also, please be aware that third parties, such as companies displaying advertisements on the Services or sites or services provided by third parties (“ ** _Third-Party Sites_** “) that may be linked to from the Services, may set cookies on your hard drive or use other means of passively collecting information about your use of their services, Third-Party Sites or content. We do not have access to, or control over, these third-party means of passive data collection.

_Information from Other Sources_

We may receive information about you, including Personal Information, from third parties, and may combine this information with other Personal Information we maintain about you. If we do so, this Policy governs any combined information that we maintain in personally-identifiable format.  
**  
Use of Personal Information**

We use Personal Information to provide services and information that you request; to enhance, improve, operate, and maintain our Services, our programs, services, websites, and other systems; to prevent fraudulent use of our Services and other systems; to prevent or take action against activities that are, or may be, in violation of our Terms of Use or applicable law; to tailor advertisements, content, and other aspects of your experience on and in connection with the Services; to maintain a record of our dealings with you; for other administrative purposes; and for any other purposes that we may disclose to you at the point at which we request your Personal Information, and pursuant to your consent.

We may also use Personal Information you provide at any time during your visit to the Website to contact you regarding products, services, and offers, both from ourselves and from third parties, that we believe you may find of interest. We allow you to opt-out from receiving marketing communications from us as described in the “Choice” section below.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

Except as described in this Policy, we will not disclose your Personal Information that we collect on the Services to third parties without your consent. We may disclose information to third parties if you consent to us doing so, as well as in the following circumstances:

_Service Providers_

We may disclose Personal Information to third-party service providers (e.g., payment processing and data storage and processing facilities) that assist us in our work. We limit the Personal Information provided to these service providers to that which is reasonably necessary for them to perform their functions, and we require them to agree to maintain the confidentiality of such Personal Information.

_Business Transfers_

Information about our users, including Personal Information, may be disclosed and otherwise transferred to an acquirer, or successor or assignee as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of company assets, or similar transaction, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which Personal Information is transferred to one or more third parties as one of our business assets.

_To Protect our Interests_

We also disclose Personal Information if we believe that doing so is in our interest to protect our property or other legal rights (including, but not limited to, enforcement of our agreements), or the rights or property of others, or otherwise to help protect the safety or security of our Services and other users of the Services.

_Compliance with Law_

We may disclose Personal Information required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, or to respond to a government request.

**Your Rights**

_Choice_

If you receive promotional e-mail from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the e-mail. You may also opt-out from receiving promotional e-mail from us, and any other promotional communications that we may send to you from time to time (e.g., by postal mail) by sending your request to us by e-mail at [privacy@extraspace.com](mailto:privacy@extraspace.com) or by writing to us at the address given at the end of this policy. Additionally, if we offer user account functionality on the Services, we may allow you to view and modify settings relating to the nature and frequency of promotional communications that you receive from us.

Please be aware that if you opt-out of receiving promotional e-mail from us, it may take up to ten business days for us to process your opt-out request, and you may receive promotional e-mail from us during that period. Additionally, even after you opt-out from receiving promotional messages from us, you will continue to receive administrative messages from us regarding our Services.

_Access_

If we offer the ability to create user accounts or profiles on our Services, you may have the ability to access and update many categories of Personal Information that you provide to us by logging in to your account and accessing your account settings. If you wish to access or amend any other Personal Information we hold about you, you may contact us at [privacy@extraspace.com](mailto:privacy@extraspace.com). We may request proof of your identity before sharing or updating such Personal Information.

If you request that we delete your Personal Information on any of our Services (via a user settings page, by e-mail, or otherwise), we will do so within a reasonable period of time, but we may need to retain some of your Personal Information in order to satisfy our legal obligations, or where we reasonably believe that we have a legitimate reason to do so.

Additionally, if you are in the European Union, you may reach out to us to request a copy of your personal information, to request a transfer of your Personal Information to a third party in certain circumstances, to withdraw any consents that you have provided for processing your Personal Information, or to request that we cease processing your Personal Information. However, please note that it may not be possible for us to cease processing all of the Personal Information we hold if we have another legal basis or requirement for maintaining such information. You also have the right to make a complaint at any time to the relevant data protection authority in your country

**Links  
**  
The Services may contain links to other websites, products, or services that we do not own or operate. For example, the Services may contain links to third-party merchants from which users may purchase sound recordings that are streamed through the Services. The Services also may contain links to Third-Party Sites such as social networking services. If you choose to visit or use any Third-Party Sites or products or services available on or through such Third-Party Sites, please be aware that this Policy will not apply to your activities or any information you disclose while using those Third-Party Sites or any products or services available on or through such Third-Party Sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third-Party Sites or any products or services on or through them. Additionally, please be aware that the Services may contain links to websites and services that we operate but that are governed by different privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies applicable to any website or service you visit other than the Services before providing any Personal Information on them.

**International Visitors**

Our servers and data centers are located in the United States. If you choose to use the Services from outside the U.S., then you should know that you are transferring your Personal Information outside of your region and into the U.S. for storage and processing. Also, we may transfer your data from the U.S. to other countries or regions in connection with storage and processing of data, fulfilling your requests, and operating the Services. You should know that each region can have its own privacy and data security laws, some of which may be less stringent as compared to those of your own region.

**Security and Retention**

We use reasonable security measures that are designed to protect personal information from accidental loss, disclosure, misuse, and destruction. Please be aware, however, that no data security measures can be guaranteed to be completely effective. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you provide to us. You transmit information to us at your own risk.

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as needed to fulfill your requests, provide the Services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**How We Respond to Do Not Track Signals**

**Children Under the Age of 13**

The Services are not directed to, and we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from, children under the age of 13. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us using the contact information below.

**Updates to this Policy**

We may occasionally update this Policy. When we do, we will also revise the “last updated” date at the beginning of the Policy. If we change this Policy in a manner that is materially less restrictive of our use or disclosure of your Personal Information, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you of the change and to obtain your consent prior to applying the change to any Personal Information that we collected from you prior to the date the change becomes effective. We encourage you to periodically review this Policy to stay informed about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Policy, please contact us using the following contact information:

Extra Space Storage Inc.  
2795 East Cottonwood Parkway, Suite 300  
Salt Lake City, UT 84121
